Who is this anyway?
こいつ… 誰だ？
アー…
gokigen yo doukashitan darou?
How are you? Is something wrong?
ごきげんよう どうかしたんだろ？
kao wo mireba isshun de wakaru yo
I can tell just by looking at you.
顔を見れば一瞬でわかるよ
senrigan senrigan? messou nai desu
Am I psychic? Of course not.
千里眼千里眼？
めっそうないです
taikutsu GIRL megumaretai no kai
Bored girl, do you want to find happiness?
退屈ガール 恵まれたいのかい
hantei wa shingi no renzoku de
Let's think it through and decide.
判定は審議の連続で
VENUS SUSTAIN
Venus Sustain.
ヴィーナスサステイン
odoru machinami
The city dances.
踊る街並み
PERFECTLY EUPHORIA
Perfectly, Euphoria!
Perfectly Euphoria！
nandemo nai youna kotoba de naitari suru shi
I end up crying over the smallest things.
何でもないような
言葉で泣いたりするし
hora bokutachi nante
Come on, our
ほら 僕たちなんて
zentei no nai
temporary passion
juubun tekido ni
lives are
十分適度に
zentei no nai
a temporary passion
DRAMATIC sa
reasonably dramatic.
ドラマチックさ
saikou no wa
the best passion
karuku SUPER STAR
We're almost like super stars!
軽くスーパースター
ORION wo nazoru konna fukai yoru
Looking up at Orion late at night.
オリオンをなぞる こんな深い夜
tsunagaretai hanasaretai
I want to connect. I want to be free.
つながりたい 離されたい
tsumari hanshinhangi acchi kocchi
Basically, I'm not sure and can't decide.
つまり半信半疑あっちこっち
shin mirai wo negau kuuzenzetsugo no
I pray for a new future. The greatest one yet.
新未来を願う 空前絶後の
kotoba ga moshi, moshi tsumugeru nara jikan ga tomaru yo
If I could spin words, time would stop.
言葉がもし もし紡げるなら
時間が止まるよ
koko de owaru hazu ga nai no ni
"There's no way it can end here."
｢ココデオワルハズガナイノニ｣
Wow, you're doing great! And then?
おぉ いいぞ！
それで？　それで？
２×７＝14　２×８＝16
Two times seven is fourteen, two times eight is sixteen,
２×９＝18
two times nine is eighteen, three times one is three,
What a smart girl you are, Kaede.
えっらいねぇ 楓は
three times two is six, three times three is nine,
When did you get so good at it?
いつの間に そんなに出来るように
なったんだ〜い？
three times four is twelve...
A long time ago.
とっくの昔だよ！
そっかぁ
Oh yeah? Well, Daddy's so proud of you!
さすが パパの娘だねぇ
Hey Dad, could you stop talking to me like that?
ねぇ お父さん
いいかげん
その話し方止めてよ！
I'm not a kid anymore.
子どもじゃないんだから
Huh?
えっ
Kaede, it's getting late. Time for bed.
楓！
もう遅いんだから 寝なさい！
Okay.
はーい
はあ…
What are you sighing about?
どーしたの？
ため息なんかついて
I was just thinking about how kids grow up
イヤ　親がいなくても
子は育つんだなって
even without their parents around.
情けない声出さないの
Don't be so depressed.
あの子ね 大事にしてたぬいぐるみ
無くしちゃって
She's just upset right now because
she lost her favorite stuffed animal.
今 機嫌悪いのよ
Oh, that's why?
えっ？
そうだったのかぁ…
I wish you were here at times like these.
こういう時
あんたが居てくれればねぇ
Can't you come home once in a while?
たまには 帰って来れないの？
イヤ 無理だって！
母ちゃんもわかってるだろ？
I can't. You understand, don't you, Mom?
俺の仕事に休みは無いんだよ
This job doesn't allow me to take time off.
仕事もいいけど
体には気を付けなさいよ！
Work is fine, but mind your health.
I will. 'Bye.
ああ　じゃ
有給休暇？
Take paid time off?!
だいぶ たまってるでしょ？
You've racked up quite a few days, haven't you?
This is a good time to use them.
いい機会だし
明日から２〜３日 ゆっくりしなさい
Relax for two or three days, starting tomorrow.
えっ でも
ヒーローが休むわけには
But a Hero cannot rest.
困るんだよねぇ
You're putting me in a difficult spot here.
労働法違反だって
マスコミに 叩かれでもしたら
The media would criticize us for violating labor laws.
But I'll be fine!
俺 平気ですから
嫌なら 辞めてもらっても
構わないんですよ
If you don't like it, you can quit.
アッ
エッ でも 万が一って時に
俺がいないと…
But what if you need me?
あっ だいじょぶ だいじょぶ
Oh, we'll be fine.
ああ
２位のバーナビー様が
いますもんね
Right, you have the great Barnaby,
the second highest ranked Hero, handling things.
エッへー
へへ…
チッ
はぁー
Hello?
あっ もしもし？
おう　俺だ！
Hey, it's me. How about it?
どうだ？
久々に １杯やんねぇか？
Want to get a drink?
今 そんな気分じゃねえんだ
I don't feel up to it right now.
付き合い悪いなあ
You're no fun.
All the other Heroes are enjoying their time off.
他のやつらだって
きっと ハネ伸ばしてんぞぉ
Sorry, ask someone else.
すまんが 他当たってくれ
H-Hey!
おっ おい！
ん？
It's so cute!
かっわいー！
ありがとう パパ！
Thanks, Daddy.
Come on! Come on over!
さぁさぁ よってらっしゃい！
見てらっしゃい！
Take a look!
入荷しても 即 品切れの
超レアもの
It's a super rare toy that sells out
as soon as we have it in stock!
大人気商品 マッドベアー！
It's our popular Mad Bear!
在庫 残りわずか
買わなきゃ 損するよ！
We only have a few left in stock!
If you don't buy one, you'll regret it!
エェッ！
This is a popular toy?
これが 大人気商品？
チッチッチッ！
You don't understand, sir.
お客さん
わかってませんねぇ
These seam lines that look like it went through surgery...
手術したような 体の縫い目
死んだ魚のような 虚ろな目
And these blank eyes that look like a dead fish...
This is what children love!
これが 子ども心をくすぐるんですよ！
But still...
イヤ　でもなぁ…
It's your chance to make a good impression on your kids.
パパの株を上げるチャンスですよ
I'll take it!
買います！
フンッ！
あーっ
Hello?
はい
あー 俺だ
悪いけど今日から休みもらうから
It's me.
Sorry, but I'm going on a vacation starting today.
あと頼んだぞ！
Take care of things while I'm gone.
珍しいですね
あなたが休暇を取るなんて
How unusual.
I never expected you to take time off from work.
アァッ…
Yeah, it feels great to know that
ああ　しばらく
おまえの顔を見ないで済むと思うと
I won't have to see your face for a while.
清々するよ
Well? What's it like, kid?
ほーら　どうなんだ？
坊主…
Huh? Hey, Bunny? Are you mad?
あぁ あれ？　おーい バディ？
怒ったのか？
ジョークなのに…
It was just a joke.
うっ…う
Mr. Maverick... I know who killed my parents.
マーべリックさん
わかったんです　僕の親を殺した犯人が
I'm heading there right now!
今から　そっちに向かうからねぇ
じゃあ 気をつけてね
Be careful.
Say, Kaede...
なぁ 楓
何？
Yeah?
You're going to love the present I got for you.
おみやげ 楽しみにしてろよ
こっちで大人気の ぬいぐるみだぞ！
It's a stuffed animal that's really popular over here.
It isn't a Mad Bear, is it?
まさか　マッドベアーじゃないよね？
ええ？
Huh?
あれだけはやめてね！
かわいくないから
Don't get me that. It's not cute at all.
アァッ　確かに あれはなぁ
かわいくないもんな
It certainly isn't cute, is it?
Anyway, are you really coming home?
っていうか…
ホントに帰って来るの？
あぁ
もう向かってるから
Yeah. I'm already on my way.
You always say that and break your promise.
そう言って
いつも 約束破るじゃん
あっ　今度こそホントだって
This time it's true.
うわっ あっ
ンダッ
What the hell?!
エッエッ　エッ
Hello? Hey, Dad?
もしもし？　ちょっと お父さん？
Hello? Dad, are you listening?
もしもし？
お父さん 聞いてるの？　もしもし…
Hello?
Sorry, Kaede.
悪い 楓
やっぱ 帰れそうにないわ
It looks like I won't be able to come home today.
ほらね！
I knew it.
あっ…
ん　だあっ！
Damn!
おっ
ワイルド タイガー
Wild Tiger, there's been a terrorist bombing at Brox Bridge!
ブロックスブリッジで
爆破テロが発生した
近くにいるんだろ？
すぐ向かってくれ！
You're nearby, aren't you? Go over there right now!
First, you want me to take a paid vacation,
有給取れって言ったり
現場に向かえって言ったり
and now you want me to head to the scene?!
どっちなんです？
Make up your mind!
Wild Tiger... Heroes have no days off.
ワイルドタイガー
ヒーローに休日なんてないぞ！
それ 俺が言ったセリフですよ！
Isn't that what I told you?!
すぐ トランスポーターを
向かわせるから
I'll send a transporter right away!
結局 こうじゃないかよ！
I knew it was going to turn out like this.
バディ 聞いたか？
You get that, Bunny?!
ブロックスブリッジで爆破テロだ
There was a terrorist bombing at Brox Bridge!
Where are you right now?
今 どこにいる？
アッバス刑務所に
向かっていたところです
I was on my way to Abas Prison.
Prison?
刑務所？
犯人がいるんです
There's a criminal there. The criminal who killed my parents.
僕の親を殺した犯人が…
You figured out who he is?!
わかったのか？
それを確かめに行こうと
思ったんですが…
I wanted to go there to confirm it.
すみません　すぐ そちらに向かいます
Sorry, I'll head on over right away.
No, go to the prison.
いや　行けよ
What?
えっ？
You've been looking for him for twenty years, right?
20年間 ずっと探してきたんだろ？
Don't worry. I'll handle this.
心配すんな
こっちは 俺が何とかする！
でも あなた１人に任せる訳には…
But I can't let you handle this alone.
俺じゃ
頼りにならねぇって言うのか？
Are you saying that you can't count on me?
うっ
お前なんかいなくたって
この程度の事件 俺１人で十分だよ
I can handle this sort of incident well enough without you.
だから さっさと行って
確かめてこい！
So go and see if you're right!
うーん…
ウッ
The Brox Bridge, which connects the Stern Medaille Area
シュテルンメダイユ地区と
ブロックス工業地区を結ぶ
ブロックスブリッジが爆破されました
and the Brox Industrial Area, has been blown up.
司法局はテロリストによる犯行を視野に
捜査を進めています
The Justice Bureau is currently investigating
this incident as a possible terrorist attack.
さーて　悪い子どこだぁ？
All right, where are those naughty kids at?!
Huh? What's that?
あっあ  あいつは…
ん？
おいおい マジかよ！
You're kidding me, right?
うっ
ボンジュール ヒーロー！
見ての通り 緊急事態よ
Bonjour, Heroes. As you can see, we have an emergency.
I don't think I need to tell you this,
言うまでもなく 犯人は全員逮捕
but arrest everyone responsible for this!
Yes, ma'am!
了解！
I'm going at full power!
全力で行くぞ
Now bring it on!
まとめて かかってこい
トッリャ！
ヤッ
アッ
Hello, there.
はい　こんちわー！　うっ
Huh?
What the hell?
何だこれ？
どうしたの？　タイガー
What's wrong, Tiger?
犯人はマッドベアー　超レアものだ
The culprit is a Mad Bear! It's super rare!
Huh?
ハァ？
知らねえのか？
Don't you know?
It has seam lines that look like it went through surgery...
“手術したような体の縫い目”
“死んだ魚のような虚ろな目”
And it has blank eyes that look like a dead fish...
よぉ おおっ
おっ ちょっ
Huh?
Hey, wait! Don't run away, damn it!
おい　逃げんな　コラッ！
えいっ
よっ
えいっ　もう逃げ場はないぞ
There's nowhere to run!
アッ
What a cocky bastard!
生意気な奴だなぁ
You're not worth thirty dollars!
お前なんか 30ドルの価値もねえんだよ
エッ？
おー えっ！
Whoa!
ぬいぐるみ？
A stuffed animal?
だから 言ってんだろ！
That's what I told you!
どっかに こいつらを操ってる
真犯人がいるはずだ
There should be a mastermind
somewhere controlling these guys!
So a NEXT is behind this...
ＮＥＸＴの仕業ってことね
あっ
今度は 何？
What is it this time?
There's been a terrorist bombing at the heliport in North Gold!
ノースゴールドのヘリポートで
爆破テロが…
How amusing. The show is getting exciting.
おもしろいじゃない　番組が盛り上がるわ
Sky High, Rock Bison, Fire Emblem, Origami Cyclone...
スカイハイ　ロックバイソン
ファイヤーエンブレム　折紙サイクロン
ここはもういいわ
Forget this area! Go to North Gold!
ノースゴールドにゴー
了解！
Yes, ma'am!
ウッフ
軍の対応はどうなってる？
How is the army dealing with this situation?!
それが…
この件は ヒーロー側で対処すると
Actually, Maverick has asked the mayor
マーベリックが市長に申し入れたらしい
to let the Heroes handle this incident.
ヒーローがここまで大きなテロを
扱った前例はないぞ
Heroes have never dealt with a terrorist incident this big!
彼らに任せて大丈夫なのか？
Can we really let them handle this?!
さあ どうする？　ヒーロー
It's your move, Heroes...
えっ
ふっふっふっ
こちらも 人形の仕業のようでござる
This seems to be the work of the dolls as well!
You mean this is all the doing of one person?!
まさか！　同一犯てこと？
おい　マジかよ
Hey, are you serious?
どうしたの？
What's wrong?
イーストゴールドと
ウエストブロンズでも
There's been a terrorist bombing
at East Gold and West Bronze!
爆破テロです
What?!
ええ？
もうすぐですわ　ジェイク様
Just a while longer, Mister Jake.
ファイヤーエンブレム　ロックバイソン
Fire Emblem, Rock Bison...
そっちは任せて
イーストゴールドへゴー
Leave this to the others and go to East Gold!
Huh? But we just got here.
あーん？　着いたばっかだぞ
What's going on?
どーなってんのよ
Blue Rose and Dragon Kid... Go to West Bronze Pier!
ブルーローズとドラゴンキッドは
ウエストブロンズの港よ
エイッ！　ハイッ！
Yes, ma'am!
Got it!
了解！
でも タイガーを１人残していいの？
But is it all right to leave Tiger on his own?
チャッ
You little!
チェッ　オラァッ
俺のことはいいから 行け！
Never mind me. Just go!
If things get rough, I'll use your Cutie Escape.
ヤバくなったら キューティエスケープ
すっからよ　あり？
Huh?
最後まで聞けー！
I'm not finished talking yet!
All right, let's do this!
よっしゃ　やるかぁ！
Powers exhausted in five seconds.
能力終了 5秒前
え？
Huh?
４　３　２…
Four, three, two, one, zero...
Oh, come on...
オイオイオイッ
ゼロ
Haven't you gotten in touch with Barnaby yet?
バーナビーとは まだ連絡つかないの？
I've been calling him, but he isn't answering.
さっきから呼びかけてますが
応答がありません
What is he doing during this emergency?
この非常事態に何してんのよっ！
Are you saying that you can't count on me?
俺じゃ
頼りにならねえって言うのか？
ふっはー…
ハッ
タッ
Yes! Dragon Kid has successfully brought down a culprit!
なんと ドラゴンキッド　犯人逮捕
ちょっと 横取りしないでよ！
Hey! Don't steal my targets!
Oh, sorry. I didn't mean to.
ごめん　つい
アッ
おっと 危ない
Look out!
A Double Escape made in the nick of time!
間一髪で ダブルエスケープ！
フッ
Fire!
ファーイ ヤッ！
ウファ
うわっ
うぉっ
でえっ えいっ
Yes!
ヨシ！
うわっはっ
Rock Bison and Fire Emblem are in trouble!
ロックバイソン ファイヤーエンブレム
ピーンチ！
スカーイハーイ
Sky... High!
It's the moment we've been waiting for!
待ってましたぁ
キング オブ ヒーロー
犯人を連続撃破だぁ
The King of Heroes has taken out several culprits at once!
Thank you very much!
ありがとうございます
これが 拙者の仕事
恩義は無用でござる
This is my job. There is no need to thank me.
折紙サイクロン　人命救助
Origami Cyclone has saved a person!
And he's on a roll of being seen in the background!
そして 見切れも絶好調
Only to be knocked out of the screen!
と思ったら フレームアウトー！
Why you...
フェッ　タァー
Damn it. Where are they coming from?
ちっきしょう
どっから湧いて出てくんだ？　こいつら
Help me!
助けてー！
オォ？
エエイッ
エイ
ああーっ
オオーワッ
トットッ オワッ トットットー
エーイ
ウォー
I'll get you out right away!
今 助けてやるからな！
This is bad. The Heroes are starting to get overwhelmed.
まずいですよ
ヒーローたちが押されはじめてます
If people see this, they're going to panic!
こんなの市民が見たら
パニックになりますよ
中継 中止したほうが
いいんじゃないすか？
Perhaps we should stop the broadcast.
You idiot. We can't let this chance slip away.
バカね
こんなチャンス逃せるわけないでしょ
同じ過ちを繰り返す気ですか
Are you going to make the same mistake again?!
あぁ…
It would be bad for our program if people turn on the Heroes,
ルナティックの時みたいに
また ヒーローバッシングが
広まりでもしたら
like they did when Lunatic appeared!
番組にとってマイナスですよ
やむを得ないわね
I guess we have no choice. Stop the broadcast!
中継はストップ
再放送ブイに切り替える
Switch over to recording for rebroadcasting.
No, continue with the program.
番組は続けるんだ
あっ
What good will it do if we don't trust the Heroes?
私たちがヒーローを信じないで
どうする
They will pull through. We must trust in them.
彼らなら 必ずやってくれる
彼らを信じるんだ
あぁ…
Hey, the King of Heroes is being overwhelmed.
おい キング オブ ヒーローが
押されているぞ
がんばれ！　ヒーロー
Hang in there, Heroes!
あぁ…
ワイルドタイガー　ピンチです
Oh, no... Wild Tiger is in danger!
He is risking his life to save a civilian!
己の身をていして
市民を救おうとしています
あっ…
うっ
All right.
よし
All preparations are complete, ma'am.
準備が整いました
Good work.
ご苦労様
Damn bastards... Getting all cocky...
あの野郎　調子に乗りやがって
もう よっと
There!
悪い　後で助けに行く
待ってろ！
Sorry, I'll come save you later! Just hold on!
オワッ タットッ
エーイ
こういうもん 使うのは しゃくだが
I don't really like using things like these,
この際しょうがねえ
but in this case, I have no choice!
ウワッ
Are you all right?
大丈夫ですか？
おっ　バニー！　なんでお前…
Bunny... Why are you here?
久しぶりのお姫様抱っこですね
It's been a while since I carried you like this.
ちょっと太りました？
Did you gain some weight?
Shut up. Put me down!
あ いや　うるせぇ！
おろせ！
What about your thing?
そっちの件はいいのか？
His prison sentence is 250 years. I can see him at any time.
そいつの刑期は250年ですから
あせらずとも会いにいけます
Besides...
それに…
えっ？
あなたには助けてもらった
借りがありますからね
I had to repay you for saving me.
All right, let's clean this place up so we can visit this guy!
よーし
じゃ さっさと片付けて
この野郎を拝みにいくぞ
Try not to get in my way.
足手まといは ごめんですよ
Smart-ass.
生意気言うな
アン？
アッ！
何だ？　この音は
What is this noise?
アァ？
Huh? What?
おお　おっおっお　何？
What is this?
何ですか？　これ
さあ？
Who knows?
Hey, this is...
おい　これって！
ウッ
無駄な抵抗は おやめください
Stop your futile resistance.
エェ？
I repeat.
繰り返しますわ
無駄な抵抗は おやめください
Stop your futile resistance.
おい 何だ？　今の声
Whose voice is that?
It's no good!
だめです
It seems that someone is jamming our signal!
どこかからか
ジャミングされてるみたいです
あぁ…
Hey, what's going on?!
おい どーなってんだ？　アニエス！
Agnes!
I don't know!
知らないわよ！
あっ
シュテルンビルト市民の皆さん
ごきげんよう
Greetings, citizens of Stern Bild.
Our name is Ouroboros.
我々の名は ウロボロス
エッ
ウロボロス
Ouroboros...
シュテルンビルトの交通網は
全て 我々が制圧しました
We have taken over Stern Bild's major traffic routes.
This city is now completely isolated.
この街は 今
完全に孤立状態にあります
In other words, every citizen has become our hostage.
つまり 市民全員が我々の
人質になったということですの
We have only one demand.
我々の要求は１つ
We want you to release our comrade
アッバス刑務所に収監されている
我が同胞を 解放することです
who is being imprisoned in Abas Prison.
If you don't give in to our demands,
要求をのまない場合
三層からなるシュテルンビルトを支える
柱の50パーセントを破壊し
we will destroy half of the pillars that support
the three levels of Stern Bild and sink this city.
この街を沈めます
What?!
何だと？
そうなったら
If that happens, I wonder how many of Stern Bild's
2000万人を超える
シュテルンビルト市民の
twenty-million-plus citizens will survive?
何割が生きていられるかしら
フッフフフ
ウッ
If you want to save your citizens, release him right away.
市民を救いたければ
速やかに解放してください
我が同胞　ジェイク・マルチネスを
Our comrade, Jake Martinez...
Jake?
ちっく…
うっ
ううーん
あぁ おーわりー
Finished.
僕が消え 遠い未来で
boku ga kie tooi mirai de kaseki ni nattara
When I die and become a fossil in the far future,
化石になったら
人は僕に何を見るだろう
hito wa boku ni nani wo miru darou?
what will people see me as?
分析して 名を付けて
bunseki shite na wo tsukete kaidoku wo shitemo
They may try to analyze, name, and understand me,
解読をしても
愛した人は僕しか知らない
aishita hito wa boku shika shiranai
but only I will know the person I loved.
ハロー 生きること
HELLO ikiru koto
Hello, existence.
君の他に 君はできない
kimi no hoka ni kimi wa dekinai
Only you alone can live your life.
輝き続ける光った星から
kagayaki tsuzukeru hikatta hoshi kara
From the bright star that continues to shine,
輝き続け 光ったあの空から
kagayaki tsuzuke hikatta ano sora kara
from that bright sky that continues to shine.
僕らは何を感じられるだろう
bokura wa nani wo kanjirareru darou?
What can we feel from it?
奇跡は宇宙だけじゃないよ
kiseki wa uchuu dake janai yo
The universe isn't the only miracle.
輝き続ける光った星から
kagayaki tsuzukeru hikatta hoshi kara
From the bright star that continues to shine,
輝き続け 光ったあの空から
kagayaki tsuzuke hikatta ano sora kara
from that bright sky that continues to shine.
目を閉じたって 閉じきれないよ
me wo tojitatte tojikirenaiyo
You can try to shut your eyes, but you can't shut out your heart.
あの星さえ 持てなかった心
ano hoshi sae motenakatta kokoro
It's something that even the stars did not possess.
はーい！
TIGER ＆ BUNNYの
ワインはロゼを選ぶほう
バーナビーです
Hi! I'm Barnaby, the member of "Tiger & Bunny"
やっと正体を現したな
ウロボロス
that prefers rose wine!
You've finally shown yourselves, Ouroboros...
折紙先輩 がんばって
この作戦が成功すれば 僕は…
Good luck, Origami!
If this plan is successful, then I can finally...
次回　TIGER ＆ BUNNY
The die is cast
Next time on TIGER & BUNNY:
See ya！
See you!